Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco. My name is Catherine and today we have an intermediate level lesson about education and university.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。我是Catherine，今天我们带来一节关于教育和大学的中级课程。
That's right. Today we're trying to find a university. We want to get some information about how much it costs and all that sort of stuff.
没错。今天我们想找一所大学。我们想了解学费之类的信息。
So, why don't we jump into the dialogue and see what's going on today.
那么，我们直接进入对话，看看今天发生了什么吧。
AmLion College
AmLion学院
I've never heard of AmLion College. Could you?
我从没听说过AmLion学院。你能介绍一下吗？
Of course, sir. Let me give you a brief overview.
当然可以，先生。让我给您一个简要的概述。
AmLion College is located in the center of New York City. The school covers a wide range of academic subjects and 80% of the courses are transferable to other state universities.
AmLion学院位于纽约市中心。学校涵盖广泛的学科领域，80%的课程可以转到其他州立大学。
And last year AmLion College was ranked number one in terms of graduate employment.
而且去年，AmLion学院在毕业生就业率方面排名第一。
Interesting. And what about the tuition fees, then?
有意思。那学费是多少呢？
You'll be looking at somewhere around $15,000 per semester.
您大概需要支付每学期15000美元左右。
Okay. Well...
好的。嗯……
And did I mention our on-campus housing? Students can stay in our newly renovated dorms for as little as $3,000 per month.
我有没有提到我们的校内住宿？学生可以住在我们新装修的宿舍，每月只需3000美元。
Sounds good. Well, I'll just grab one of your flyers.
听起来不错。那我拿一份你们的宣传单吧。
Sir, you got the wrong flyer. Sir! Sir!
先生，您拿错宣传单了。先生！先生！
Alright, we're back. So now let's take a look at some language on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了。现在让我们看看“语言要点”中的一些语言点。
Language Takeaway
语言要点
So, first up, Marco, we've got this word, transferable.
首先，Marco，我们有一个词，“transferable”。
In the dialogue, the representative from AmLion College said that 80% of the courses are transferable to other state universities.
在对话中，AmLion学院的代表说80%的课程可以转到其他州立大学。
Okay, so before we talk about transferable, what is the difference here? We have two words, college and university.
好的，在讨论“transferable”之前，这里有什么区别？我们有两个词，“college”和“university”。
So why is he saying that you can transfer your courses from AmLion College to another university?
那他为什么说你可以把课程从AmLion学院转到另一所大学呢？
Well, college and university are words that we use in English to describe higher education.
嗯，“college”和“university”是英语中用来描述高等教育的词。
That means education after high school.
也就是高中之后的教育。
And a college is usually just for people who are in the middle of their studies.
而“college”通常只适用于正在学习中途的人。
A college is usually just for bachelor's students, students who are doing their first four years out of high school.
“college”通常只针对本科生，也就是高中毕业后头四年的学生。
But a university is usually a larger institution that has bachelor's degree students as well as master's degree students and PhD candidates.
但“university”通常是一个更大的机构，既有本科生，也有硕士生和博士生。
And so while a college is for 18 to 22 year olds, a university can have students of all ages who are doing sometimes very advanced degrees like postdoctoral work.
所以，“college”面向18到22岁的学生，而“university”可以有各个年龄段的学生，有时他们攻读非常高级的学位，比如博士后研究。
Okay, very interesting. And so this is why the person mentions that 80% of the courses are transferable to other state universities.
好的，很有意思。所以这就是为什么那个人提到80%的课程可以转到其他州立大学。
So transferable means that you can transfer, you can move to another university.
所以“transferable”意味着你可以转学，你可以转到另一所大学。
So everything that you've studied, you can take with you.
所以你学过的所有东西都可以带走。
That's right. So a lot of people like to start at a college or vice versa.
没错。所以很多人喜欢先从“college”开始，或者反过来。
They just start at a big university and transfer to a college.
他们只是先在一所大型大学开始，然后转到“college”。
And so it's important to know that your courses can be transferred as well.
所以知道你的课程也可以转学很重要。
So if I studied Spanish for two years, I can transfer that, I can transfer those courses to my new school.
所以如果我学了两年西班牙语，我可以转学，我可以把这些课程转到我的新学校。
Right, so you don't have to start over.
对，这样你就不用从头开始了。
Right.
对。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
And well, obviously, one of the big questions when you're picking a university is the tuition fee.
嗯，显然，选择大学时的一个大问题是学费。
So tuition is the amount of money it costs to attend a university for usually a year.
所以“tuition”是上大学通常一年所需的费用。
Tuition fees is the actual money you have to pay.
“Tuition fees”是你实际需要支付的钱。
So you can say, I can't afford my tuition fees this year, so I will be getting a part time job.
所以你可以说，我今年付不起学费，所以我打算找份兼职。
Okay. And so this is what tuition fees are.
好的。这就是“tuition fees”的意思。
In school, you call it tuition.
在学校里，你叫它“tuition”。
You don't say how much it costs.
你不说多少钱。
You ask, what is the tuition?
你问，学费是多少？
What's the tuition exactly?
具体学费是多少？
Okay. And he mentioned that it was around $15,000 per semester.
好的。他提到每学期大约15000美元。
So this is interesting. Is this the year?
这很有意思。这是指一年吗？
No, a semester is half of an academic year.
不，“semester”是学年的一半。
All right. So an academic year is usually September to May or June.
好的。所以学年通常是九月到五月或六月。
And a semester is half of that.
而“semester”是它的一半。
So first semester or fall semester is the study period between September and December or January.
所以第一学期或秋季学期是九月到十二月或一月之间的学习期。
That's right. Okay.
没错。好的。
So basically what we could deduce is that this university costs $15,000 per semester or about $30,000 per year.
所以基本上我们可以推断，这所大学每学期15000美元，或者每年大约30000美元。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
And well, he also mentioned about the on-campus housing.
嗯，他还提到了校内住宿。
All right. So on-campus is pretty straightforward.
好的。“on-campus”很直接。
It means that this housing option where you live and sleep is on the campus.
意思是这种你生活和睡觉的住宿选择在校园内。
And a university campus is not one building.
而大学校园不是一栋楼。
It's many, many buildings together.
它是很多很多栋楼在一起。
Sometimes there are classrooms and there are laboratories and there's a cafeteria.
有时有教室、实验室和食堂。
But there's also housing.
但也有住宿。
And most housing comes in one style.
大多数住宿有一种风格。
What's the style they mentioned in today's dialogue?
今天对话中提到的风格是什么？
A dorm. This is where university students usually live if they live on campus.
“Dorm”。这是大学生如果住在校园里通常住的地方。
They have dorms.
他们有宿舍。
So dorm is short for dormitory.
所以“dorm”是“dormitory”的缩写。
And it basically means that it's an apartment building for students or even sometimes workers that's very close to where they'll be studying or working.
它基本上意味着这是一栋为学生甚至有时为工人准备的公寓楼，离他们学习或工作的地方很近。
So what is the difference between a dorm and an apartment?
那么“dorm”和“apartment”有什么区别？
Well, I can give you an example.
嗯，我可以给你举个例子。
Some dorms are very fancy, but my dorm at university was very simple.
有些宿舍很豪华，但我在大学时的宿舍很简单。
So I lived in one bedroom with another girl.
所以我和另一个女孩住在一个卧室里。
There were two beds and no bathroom.
有两张床，没有浴室。
And so everyone on that floor of the building shared bathrooms.
所以那层楼的所有人都共用浴室。
And the bathrooms were, you know, there's six showers and four toilets or whatever.
浴室里有六个淋浴间和四个马桶之类的。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
Yeah, I think this is the main thing with a dorm is usually you don't have a kitchen.
是的，我认为宿舍的主要特点是通常没有厨房。
You don't have usually your own bathroom.
通常没有自己的浴室。
And so it's just basically a room and a bedroom.
所以基本上只是一个房间和一个卧室。
And then you share everything else with other people.
然后其他所有东西都和别人共用。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
A lot of great things related to college.
有很多与大学相关的好内容。
I think this is very good vocab for you, especially if you're considering going to college or something like that.
我觉得这些词汇对你很有用，特别是如果你考虑上大学或类似的事情。
Especially if you're considering going to college or maybe you want to continue your study.
特别是如果你考虑上大学，或者想继续深造。
So why don't we go back.
那我们为什么不回顾一下呢。
Let's listen to this dialogue again.
让我们再听一遍这段对话。
And we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
然后我们会回来进行流利度训练。
I've never heard of AmLion College.
我从没听说过AmLion学院。
Could you?
你能吗？
Of course, sir.
当然可以，先生。
Let me give you a brief overview.
让我给你简单介绍一下。
AmLion College is located in the center of New York City.
AmLion学院位于纽约市中心。
The school covers a wide range of academic subjects.
这所学校涵盖广泛的学科领域。
And 80% of the courses are transferable to other state universities.
而且80%的课程可以转到其他州立大学。
And last year, AmLion College was ranked number one in terms of graduate employment.
去年，AmLion学院在毕业生就业率方面排名第一。
Interesting.
有意思。
And what about the tuition fees then?
那学费呢？
You'll be looking at somewhere around $15,000 per semester.
你大概需要支付每学期15000美元左右。
Okay.
好的。
Well.
嗯。
And did I mention our on-campus housing?
我有没有提到我们的校内住宿？
Students can stay in our newly renovated dorms for as little as $3,000 per month.
学生可以住在我们新装修的宿舍，每月只需3000美元。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Well, I'll just grab one of your flyers.
那我拿一份你们的宣传册吧。
Sir, you got the wrong flyer.
先生，你拿错宣传册了。
Sir.
先生。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at these three phrases we've picked out for you on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看我们为流利度训练挑选的三个短语。
Fluency Builder
流利度训练
So again, when the person who was speaking for this college was describing it,
所以，当这位为这所学院介绍的人描述它时，
they said that the school covers a wide range of academic subjects.
他们说这所学校涵盖广泛的学科领域。
Now this phrase, wide range, is something you'll hear in a lot of different contexts.
这个短语“wide range”你会在很多不同的语境中听到。
What does it mean, Marco?
它是什么意思，Marco？
That's right.
没错。
It means that they have a variety, a very big variety of subjects.
意思是他们有各种各样的、非常多的学科。
So they don't only focus, for example, on business.
所以他们不仅仅专注于，比如说，商业。
They may have arts, they may have engineering, business, etc.
他们可能有艺术、工程、商业等等。
So if you're studying at a university and they offer one course, they offer English,
所以如果你在一所大学学习，他们只提供一门课程，比如英语，
is that a wide range of subjects?
那算是广泛的学科吗？
No, no, that's not a wide range.
不，不，那不算广泛。
So basically, a wide range of subjects would be that you can have many, many, many choices.
所以基本上，广泛的学科意味着你有很多很多选择。
Okay.
好的。
Well, after that, we also had a great phrase when we were discussing tuition fees.
嗯，之后我们在讨论学费时还有一个很好的短语。
So the visitor asked, what about the tuition fees?
所以来访者问，学费怎么样？
And the answer was, you'll be looking at somewhere around $15,000.
回答是，你大概需要支付15000美元左右。
Now, you'll be looking at is a very, very strange phrase, right?
现在，“you'll be looking at”这个短语非常非常奇怪，对吧？
Well, it's not strange, but it might sound strange to non-native English speakers.
嗯，它并不奇怪，但对非英语母语者来说可能听起来奇怪。
Right.
对。
It's actually a very common phrase, especially when you're talking to salesmen.
这其实是一个很常见的短语，特别是当你和销售人员交谈时。
They don't want to say, you'll have to pay or you have to pay or anything like this.
他们不想说“你必须付”或“你得付”之类的话。
They'll say, well, you'll be looking at somewhere around $15,000.
他们会说，嗯，你大概需要支付15000美元左右。
And that means you are expected to pay this amount of money.
这意味着你预计要付这么多钱。
But they don't really say pay.
但他们实际上没说“付”这个字。
So this is the key thing.
这就是关键所在。
All right.
好的。
So this is the price.
所以这是价格。
This is the price tag.
这是价签。
And this is something that, like you're saying, salespeople say so that you don't have to say,
这就像你说的，是销售人员说的，这样你就不用说，
well, the price of this is $30,000.
嗯，这个价格是30000美元。
So another good context for this phrase would be like a car dealership.
所以这个短语的另一个好语境是像汽车经销商那里。
If I'm buying a car and I see a beautiful new Ford Mustang and I say, well, how much does this cost?
如果我要买车，看到一辆漂亮的新款福特野马，我说，嗯，这车多少钱？
What would you, as the car dealer, say?
作为汽车经销商，你会怎么说？
I'll say, well, you'll be looking at around $30,000.
我会说，嗯，你大概需要支付30000美元左右。
I don't know.
我不知道。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a way of saying you'll have to pay.
所以这是一种说“你得付”的方式。
And, well, the guy wasn't really convinced.
而且，嗯，那个人似乎不太信服。
I think it was kind of expensive because dorms were also $3,000 per month.
我觉得有点贵，因为宿舍也要每月3000美元。
So he was like, well, sounds good.
所以他就像，嗯，听起来不错。
Well, I'll just grab one of your flyers.
嗯，我拿一份你们的宣传册吧。
All right.
好的。
So this phrase, sounds good, is something that English speakers use all the time.
所以这个短语“sounds good”是英语使用者经常用的。
I personally use it very, very often.
我个人非常非常常用。
And it's another way of saying okay.
这是说“好的”的另一种方式。
Yeah.
是的。
So if you agree with someone, you say sounds good.
所以如果你同意某人，你就说“sounds good”。
So should we meet at 7 for the movie tonight?
那我们今晚7点见面看电影怎么样？
Yeah, sure.
嗯，当然。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
All right.
好的。
It's another way of saying yes, good, okay, very well.
这是表示“是”、“好”、“行”、“非常好”的另一种说法。
That's right.
没错。
So sounds good.
所以听起来不错。
Great stuff.
太棒了。
Why don't we take a break?
我们为什么不休息一下呢？
Let's listen to everything one more time, and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们再听一遍所有内容，我们一会儿就回来。
I've never heard of AmLion College.
我从没听说过AmLion学院。
Could you?
你能吗？
Of course, sir.
当然可以，先生。
Let me give you a brief overview.
让我给你简单介绍一下。
AmLion College is located in the center of New York City.
AmLion学院位于纽约市中心。
The school covers a wide range of academic subjects,
学校涵盖广泛的学科领域，
and 80% of the courses are transferable to other state universities.
并且80%的课程可以转到其他州立大学。
And last year, AmLion College was ranked number one in terms of graduate employment.
去年，AmLion学院在毕业生就业率方面排名第一。
Interesting.
有意思。
And what about the tuition fees, then?
那学费呢？
You'll be looking at somewhere around $15,000 per semester.
你大概需要每学期15000美元左右。
Okay.
好的。
Well...
嗯……
And did I mention our on-campus housing?
我有没有提过我们的校内住宿？
Students can stay in our newly renovated dorms for as little as $3,000 per month.
学生可以住在我们新装修的宿舍，每月只需3000美元。
Sounds good.
听起来不错。
Well, I'll just grab one of your flyers.
嗯，我就拿一张你们的宣传单。
Sir, you got the wrong flyer.
先生，你拿错宣传单了。
Sir!
先生！
All right, so universities in the United States, they have a very...
好的，所以美国的大学，它们有非常……
They have a...
它们有……
They're infamous for being very expensive.
它们以非常昂贵而闻名。
That's right.
没错。
And so we discussed the difference between colleges and universities,
我们讨论了学院和大学之间的区别，
but I think it's important to also talk about the difference between public and private schools.
但我认为讨论公立和私立学校之间的区别也很重要。
Public schools are schools that are paid for by the government or that are subsidized,
公立学校是由政府支付或补贴的学校，
so the government pays part of them.
所以政府承担部分费用。
And these are schools that tend to be cheaper than private schools.
这些学校通常比私立学校便宜。
So private schools can be as much as $50,000 for one year of study.
所以私立学校一年的学费可能高达50000美元。
So, for example, the famous ones like Harvard or Stanford, those are private schools.
比如，著名的哈佛或斯坦福，这些都是私立学校。
Those are private schools, but the University of California is a public institution.
那些是私立学校，但加州大学是公立机构。
The University of Illinois, for example, is another public institution.
例如，伊利诺伊大学是另一个公立机构。
So there are many different options in the United States.
所以在美国有很多不同的选择。
I think usually the state universities have the name of the state in them.
我认为通常州立大学的名字里都带有州名。
So University of Florida is probably state university.
所以佛罗里达大学很可能是州立大学。
That's right, but you have to be careful because the University of Pennsylvania is a private university.
没错，但你要小心，因为宾夕法尼亚大学是私立大学。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
Yeah, it's an Ivy League school, so it's one of the oldest schools in America,
是的，它是常春藤盟校，是美国最古老的学校之一，
and it's like Harvard or Yale. It's very, very high quality.
就像哈佛或耶鲁一样。质量非常高。
This is something that they always mention when talking about universities in the States.
这是他们在谈论美国大学时经常提到的一点。
They always say it's an Ivy League school, just like you said right now.
他们总是说这是常春藤盟校，就像你刚才说的那样。
What does it mean if a university is Ivy League?
一所大学是常春藤盟校意味着什么？
Well, a league is just a group, right?
嗯，联盟就是一个团体，对吧？
And so some of the first universities in the United States formed this group called the Ivy League,
所以美国一些最早的大学组成了这个叫常春藤联盟的团体，
and I think it used to have to do with the sports.
我认为它最初与体育有关。
These teams would play each other in sports, but I could be wrong.
这些队伍会在体育比赛中互相竞争，但我可能说错了。
But anyway, in the 18th century, these were schools for men,
但不管怎样，在18世纪，这些是男子学校，
and there were seven Ivy League schools for men, and then there were the sister schools for women.
有七所男子常春藤盟校，还有对应的女子学校。
Wellesley, Radcliffe, these are the sister schools.
韦尔斯利学院、拉德克利夫学院，这些都是女子学校。
And so nowadays, both men and women can go to all these universities,
现在，男女都可以上所有这些大学，
and so we just talk about them as the Ivy Leagues.
所以我们统称它们为常春藤盟校。
And the Ivy League schools that are most famous are Harvard, Yale, Brown,
最著名的常春藤盟校是哈佛、耶鲁、布朗、
University of Pennsylvania, Columbia, things like that.
宾夕法尼亚大学、哥伦比亚大学等等。
So talking about universities and colleges, I have heard also the community college.
说到大学和学院，我还听说过社区学院。
Yeah, that can be a lot more affordable.
是的，那可能便宜得多。
That's something that's, because it's a community college, it's usually something you go to back near your home.
那是，因为是社区学院，通常你可以在家附近就读。
Because colleges and universities, sometimes people travel very, very far to go to these schools.
因为学院和大学，有时人们会去很远的地方上学。
But community colleges are available to people in your own community, and you can take night classes.
但社区学院面向你所在社区的人开放，你可以上夜校。
You can do a lot of different things at them.
你可以在那里做很多不同的事情。
They're great resources. They're a lot more affordable than other schools.
它们是很好的资源。比其他学校便宜得多。
And a lot of people like to go to them because they don't have to pay these expensive fees for housing like dorms or for travel.
很多人喜欢去那里，因为他们不必支付昂贵的住宿费（如宿舍）或旅行费。
And they're a great option for people.
对人们来说，这是一个很好的选择。
So community colleges, colleges, and universities are the major distinctions.
所以社区学院、学院和大学是主要的区别。
There is a lot to talk about on this subject, especially if you're a student or you're a professional,
这个话题有很多可以讨论的，特别是如果你是个学生或专业人士，
considering doing a master's abroad or you want to go to the States or Canada to study.
考虑在国外读硕士，或者想去美国或加拿大学习。
There's a lot of things to take into consideration.
有很多事情需要考虑。
So this is a great topic. We really want to hear from you if you have any other questions or doubts.
所以这是一个很棒的话题。如果你有其他问题或疑问，我们真的很想听听你的意见。
You can always find us at EnglishPod.com.
你随时可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
We hope to see you guys there. Until next time.
我们希望能在那里见到你们。下次见。
Bye.
再见。